get into the image I'm so we're starting
to record now are my friends reminding
me here that um yeah markdown is a big
part of hacking we were listening to the
hacker playlist and we were like leave
more leave better well formatted
messages in your
ransomware because you know how to write
markdown and Apollo is saying you know
you know knowing how to write reports in
markdown is a big part of the security
profession and it's actually one of the
reasons I got out of U going down that
path is because 50% of the job is
writing a really solid documented report
and that means lots of code Snippets and
lots of I mean markdown if you didn't
have markdown and you were writing a
cyber security you know vulnerability
assessment how the hell would you do
that right because you want to
constantly mix you cutting and pasting
from the command line you're putting you
know your code into the document and so
so so yeah learning markdown is actually
and a critical skill for cyber security
of all things because you're going to be
writing and communicating and whether it
be with your Vic or your
customer so we are doing a video right
now um last video we're going to do is
how to do images and again
screenshotting in a cyber security
report is a thing so pay attention this
is how you do it um it's not too hard my
friends it's actually
really easy in order to do that we're
going to have to actually create an
image but before we do we are going to
go back to our GitHub site that we
should have already
started and here you'll see you'll see
that actually I had links and images
before and we went ahead and made one
we're going to make another uh just for
for images md- images. MD uh we're
putting this in our notes directory uh
we're going to create
this and let's see images here we go
um and as you can see uh it's pretty
darn
easy get uh ready uh here comes uh an
image uh link now the way I'm going to
do this I'm not even going to tell you
any other way to do this uh because it's
just a bad idea um this is an image
of uh what should we do an image of of
of Elliot I want do an image of Elliot
okay let's go find an image of Elliot
hopefully we don't
get uh Elliot Mr robot
images uh there he is our good friend
Elliot um oh I like that one a lot
that's a nice one and so I'm going to
inspect
element I'm going to find the image link
is it even have an image link I don't
know if it does let's go see there it is
current Source you see that image link
right there we're going to copy that
image link out of
there uh copy and um we're going to go
ahead and use an external image and then
I'm we're going to upload an image and
I'll show you how to do that as well so
how do we here let's see if we can paste
it paste that image in um so there's our
our Elliot image and how do I do it well
it the reason it's so much like a link
is it looks an awful lot like a link in
fact if you do it without the final bit
it we'll see that it'll actually link to
it so this is how you know it works if
you click on the link and it takes you
to this site um then you know it's
working we're not going to do that
because it'll throw away my changes if
you know if you click on it and you or
you hover over and you can see the link
down the bottom left is going to that
place um then when you hit down on Ed uh
on edit here the only thing you have to
do to make it an inline link an inline
image is stick an exclamation point in
front of it
so if you do that it will actually
download the image and wow look at that
there's Mr Elliott he's inside of our we
you know we kind of own that thing by
the way it's it's at this point that I I
need to tell you that if you link
externally to someone else's image
source like that without copyright
attribution you could be violating the
law so just make sure you don't do that
um rather famously Twitter got called on
the carpet for allowing that to happen
people were you know linking in images
and they were showing up on Twitter even
though know they were copyrighted from
other locations that were not allowed to
be reproduced in that way it's up to you
to find that out um but if you want to
if you wanted to pull in the document
like that uh yeah we're going to talk
about SVG and image formats as well uh
we're actually going to do that today
right now um so so this particular image
is a
JPEG uh which means you know it's an
image now that same image if I wanted to
steal that image how could I do it um if
I wanted to steal that image I think you
guys know uh I can go to that URL I can
um where is
it it's probably already copied but
we're going to get it anyway because
it's a JPEG image uh we're going to copy
this and we're going to paste it paste
and go and you get Mr Robot um and so so
there we go we got this this great jpeg
image um this image is being served up
by This Server right here on be hunts if
I want to steal it um and I just do save
image as by the way this may not be
stealing depending on where you're going
we're going to save it as a file name
and downloads this original file name
let's change the name to Elliott um and
let's call it elliot. jpg and click on
Save we're going to talk about image
formats later so don't worry we'll get
there um but uh XKCD can go away common
Mark can go away stack edit can sorry
for the flashbang that is not my fault
I I mean this is a s I guess I could put
the should I put the should I put should
we do it right now I'll do it another
day I'll do it I'll do another video
about how to how to make a dark mode um
so anyway we got this big long one right
but but I what happens if that goes away
I want that image to be in my project
all the time right well here's how you
do it so this is actually pretty damn
cool on GitHub um you can go find the
download and uh there's Elliot and you
can drag the picture right into the file
um oops me see there we go you can drag
it uh at least you used to be able to
did they change it attaching files by
dragging and dropping select or pasting
them uh oh I think I have to drag it
over into this
window yeah I think you have to drag it
into this window there we go okay so
there we go it uploaded it and that is
uniquely that is a unique um thing on
gith Isn't that cool though look at that
it automatically added notes assets blah
blah blah and it put that entire thing
right into my repo for me automatically
and I can put here I can put uh this is
an image of Elliot I would still leave
the text because why because the text
becomes um the text becomes a a uh a
part of it so update MD images and um I
think it's interesting about this is if
you go to the notes directory it did not
make an assets
directory that's super interesting to me
I did not know that but the takeaway
from this is if you're using and you
will you're going to be using markdown a
lot when you submit uh tickets and
different things to GitHub and you want
to take a screenshot of the error or the
bug or something like that you just have
to take the screenshot and drag it in
and and GitHub will do the rest it'll
upload it for you um and uh they're
tired to your repo if you remove the
repo private repo to it makes it Go
unavailable nice um I did find it
interesting though that the that the
link to the video to the to the thing is
not um it does not appear to
be um it I mean let's let's what is the
what is the URL again so let's look at
the code the code is get notes assets so
it's interesting because this is
suggesting that um we have an assets
subdirectory under notes but we can't
see it which I find super fascinating
because that means it it actually added
it to our repo even though uh there is
you can't it's I mean what happens if I
had an assets directory would I put it
in there I don't know the point is that
this URL which is a fully qualified URL
is pointing to the image in question um
you can also use local images so another
way to do this um if I were to say uh
and this is actually what I was trying
to do um you can upload the image this
way uh cancel actually commit image
changes um yeah let's go ahead and do
this so you can another way you can do
that uh us this is what it use for
issues yes it is um so let's go ahead
and
say wait where's the upload file thing
where is it I know I know it's there
somewhere where is the upload
file I
there cops file tree
cancel
notes oh here it is ADD file upload file
so if you want the file to be in your
repo instead of in your assets thing you
can click on upload choose your files
you can also drag it here uh but if you
do choose file and go to our downloads
find Elliott and put him there uh by the
way I'm using Windows because it's
better for streaming and playing zipped
and games than Linux on the desktop
um so we're doing that now it says
elliot. jpg and now we can use what's
called a local image link so we can go
to uh MD here uh whoops wrong one we go
to
images here we go and go edit that file
and now instead of this we could
actually change I mean I'm going to
leave that in there uh or you can say or
uh we could use a local image ref um now
I can put the images refs online here
but it's a bad idea I I'm a firm
believer um unless you are using
something unless you kind of maybe you
want like a a little um smiley face or
something like that in line with your
text um I generally think that's a bad
idea anyway I would just use an emoji
for that because there's plenty to cover
or anything I would want to do and but
usually when I have an image is some
sort of screenshot or some illustra
and so I tend to put it as its own block
um and you know with with the adequate
line returns before and after it um and
if you do that then you can actually do
this instead um and again just to show
you that um the text is optional the
text is what gets shown as alternative
text um and you can go put this in here
um it no it's not possible no it's not I
don't want to fight with you about that
it's absolute crap um so Elliot uh. jpg
um I I have 12 hour video proving it so
we're going to we go ahead and preview
this um and you see it's the same image
the difference is is that this image is
now traveling along with the rest of my
source so if I'm actually if I can do
commit changes here um I hit click on
Commit changes and I can clone this
thing anytime I want want to I can clone
RBX r- GH test1 sln notes and now um sub
modules okay wait what uh is did it say
notes or not notes cannot resol POS name
oh it's because it's private whoopsy
Daisy uh all right one last thing Su uh
sudu D RBX Rob G I just want to show you
why you might want it in there instead
of in your assets because
reasons right um so clone RX Rob GH test
one SL notes let's see if we can get it
okay so here we go now it's all cloned
and there's Elliot there's the Elliot
picture uh I'm not on a graphic system
so I'd have to just use file or
someplace like that to to check it uh by
the way jpeg is a really fun places to
hide confidential data um yeah you can
you can put all kinds of cool things in
there you want to like hide a password
or or or like an Easter egg you can put
them in kind of J inside of J it's
really fun um so anyway this is this is
how all those things look from here uh
if I were editing them from the command
line which we are not covering yet we'll
get there eventually so so that's it
that's it for images um uh they are
pretty basic um uh in terms of markdown
images now in this particular video I'm
going to go ahead and I'm going to cover
very briefly um the different types of
images and um I'm going to just
summarize it at the very highest level
so that you can go and look it up okay
because I it's just such a long topic
and it's more of a design topic it's
less of a how to do markdown or even how
to have a technical job contact content
this is more about this is more about
design okay but I do want to give since
we're this is the only video that we're
going to talk about images at all um
other than how to do an HTML image tag
that's equivalent to what markdown
produces this is the only time we're
going to talk about images and when to
use them and what types to use and I'm
going to do a very high level summary uh
I'm just going to describe it to you and
you'll at least know what to look for so
the there are two types of images in the
world there are roster images and there
are vector images Vector images are
files that contain instructions about
how to draw the thing how to present the
thing and raster images are literally
the data for each one of the pixelated
points the bits of the image now that
that obviously is an incredible
simplification of the differences
between these things but that at the
highest level is the most important
thing for you to take away you don't
need to be a web designer to understand
the value and differences of those two
things so vector graphics and SVG images
scalable vector graphics scalable is
really key there uh are images that
originated from postcript which was
invented in part by uh by Apple who then
spun it off into a company called Adobe
which you may have heard of uh that then
went on to create printers that can
create exactly perfect fonts that are
scalable uh all the way up to huge
banners and that they invented the a
postcript which was by the way also
based on sgml sound familiar we talked
about HTML coming from HML if you want a
deep dive on that it's pretty
interesting stuff but you really don't
need to all you need to know is that
scalable vector graphics svgs are the
industry standard for images that need
to scale without losing resolution and
that is any kind of graphic art that's
um you know presentations that have um
you know maybe line art in them uh
banners kind of things um anything that
you would do in post and um you know uh
inkscape which is a one of the number
one free available um Vector art uh
things or uh the Adobe equivalent um why
am I blanking on right now it's not
Photoshop it's illustr illustrator
illustrator so you know that's for
creating line arts kinds of things now
you know as soon as you take a picture
of it though right and you're capturing
pixels and people are saying things like
oh it has a bigger sensor so it has
higher resolution now you're talking
about the bits world you're talking
about individual little dots that are
being drawn right and now you're talking
about things that have resolution right
an SVG strictly speaking doesn't have a
resolution it can be drawn anywhere at
any size and that is why most people
will choose use svgs for icons and for
graphics and things like that right but
they are a much bigger deal and they're
much much harder to render so because
believe it or not raster images are
easier to render because they just have
to decide what color to make the pixel
on the screen and they don't have to do
a bunch of complicated mathematics to
decide how to draw the bazer graph curve
or whatever is is included in the
graphic so even though svgs are enabled
there's another problem with svgs before
we leave them um sbgs can also o be
animated and I I wish I had it right now
I have an animated SVG uh that I made
for skill stack um that has the the logo
kind of pulsing and and it actually has
a musical background and it has several
uh Easter eggs in the image that you can
click on that will do different things
because svgs are themselves uh XML
documents uh which are in every way
compatible with you know they can be
shown in the web by itself and that's a
very very long separate video about XML
xhtml and all of that scalable vector
graphics are written in XML so so or
Microsoft Word docs um and ultimately
that gets converted into postcript but
you don't need to know that the point is
that they can do many many other things
and for that reason a lot of times
scalable vector graphics are banned in
fact last I heard GitHub doesn't even
allow them I think they finally gave in
on that
um because if you allow some random
person to put a scalable Vector graphic
onto your website you're allowing
anybody who goes to that website to run
code and they run code in the browser
and that causes a lot of people to be
very uncomfortable um it's the reason
that GitHub stopped allowing HTML
certain HTML tags in the markdown and so
I mean even though scalable vector
graphics is are much much smaller
because they're just instructions right
a bunch of text instruction
um they tend to be denied because it
takes more to use them uh to render them
and it's it's scarier because it's
actually runable code and so you can put
all kinds of things in there and um for
better or worse so that's one of the
reasons they don't get used um in fact
it's it's you know people regularly hack
sites by creating an SVG and getting
someone to put it on their website um so
there's
that the other thing you can do but a
raster image raster image is very
innocuous there's nothing bad about a
raster image except for you have to have
depending on the resolution you get a
bigger image because you get so many
little dots in there right the
rasterization how many dots do I have
per inch or per whatever what's my DPI
what's my you know these are all design
terms that I don't want to get into But
ultimately it's how clear is the image
depending on what you're seeing um 72
DPI is the standard by the way for
screens most screens in in even in 2024
so you don't need much more resolution
than that you certainly don't need 4K if
you ever try to open a 4K image on a on
most computer screens you know you don't
it's way more and in fact most sites
won't even let you upload uh files that
are that large so raster stuff gets
bigger and smaller depending on the
resolution um you can always shrink down
and maintain almost always you can
shrink down uh from a higher resolution
to a smaller one and
maintain um you know quality but you
can't go the other way you can't go the
other way there there are some pretty
amazing algorithms now that are coming
out that are filling in the empty spaces
when you're trying to make something
bigger but for the most part you want
the highest possible resolution and then
you can shrink it down and we'll see
this in in HTML when we get in but uh
over the years it's not as relevant as
it used to be but when you know when
internet speeds are faster now but at
the time you used to be able to provide
multiple different resolutions depending
on uh you know what the browser
supported and that's actually something
called Progressive enhancement which
we'll talk about with pwas we'll have a
separate video about what does it even
mean what does Progressive enhancement
mean why should you care um as a
designer you should think about that not
just for web design but but in in every
other way part of your world you should
think about Progressive enhancement um
well again separate video about that so
you want to do what is the minimum what
is the maximum image size that's ever
going to be needed and you take a
picture at that size a screenshot of
that size but most of the time you're
going to be shrinking stuff down because
GitHub or other things are not going to
let you upload images above a certain
size right so that's a rastered image
what are the rastered image formats out
there the number one format for raster
image uh is PNG um and PNG is kind of a
replacement to GIF um if you run across
internet information about GIF that says
that you can't use it because of
copyright that is outdated information
the copyright is no longer a thing it's
it's it's laps for several years so you
can happily use animated gifts you can
use the gift format if you wish uh it's
just lot efficient the gift for uh the
gift format is really old it does have a
built-in bug which allows it to be
animated animated gifts are built on a
bug they're not built on they're built
on a a bug that was uh they're a total
Hack That was designed to allow them to
kind of come in uh you know to increase
the resolution over time and so by
allowing that they the people who hacked
to give gifts to do animation they use
that functionality of the gift to turn
it into an animation uh that was never
its intent and gifts are ridiculously in
inefficient and bad and you shouldn't
use them unless you really want
animation through GIF animation um that
PNG is the modern version of that sort
of thing uh jpg is another rasterized
format that is primarily used for
photographs um there's tip which is you
know uncompressed whatsoever format so
give PNG and jpeg are all compressed
formats they have uh a level of
compression that makes the file sizes
much much much smaller um at the cost of
you know this compression artifacts and
um I don't I mean that's probably too
much geekery you probably don't want to
know much more than that but I actually
worked on the jpeg 201 te for a while um
working in the metadata and stuff
speaking of metadata we should probably
mention that every single one of these
image formats contains security
vulnerabilities um and what I mean by
Security in this case is not it's not
like they're going to hack your computer
it means they're going to hack your
location um every single uh PNG is
lossless I did not know thank you for
that um is GIF lossless I don't I think
GIF is compressed right so that actually
might be a reason to pick PNG over jpeg
U because jpeg is a compressed format
and I think PNG is lless that's another
reason it's a very modern format PNG is
by far there's also um was it web I
forget it what's the web version the
open version of GIF P just use P
seriously just use PNG unless it's a
photograph then use tip I mean use GI or
JF are we gonna fight about
this just 26 I did not know that uh it
only supports sub over image did not
know that these are these are great it's
great information so you know if you're
going use a JPEG if it's a for most
things you're going to be a Apex be a
photo right um You there's is it webg I
think it is a Aug is another one there's
a couple other formats that most web
browsers will support but just use uh
PNG or jpeg I mean really unless you
want animated gift the end there's
really no more to say about that use an
SVG if you want something so that's the
end of it if if you want to dig into
these things these people really geek
out about this stuff but I was talking
about privacy um I think jpeg is the
biggest offender here but any camera
unless you explicitly turn it off is
going to include position data uh and
other stuff and you know now with AI
with you know facial recognition stuff
like that you take a picture put on the
internet you know you pretty much uh
handing over Privacy Information all the
time even if it's your mom doing it um I
think the important thing to note here
is you are you might not want people to
know your position right and by the way
there are so many ways they can analyze
a picture that you've taken without gpg
without um GPS information they can find
out where you are don't just just ask
shy La
buff that's kind of a a meme reference
sh LA's uh sh lau's flag is like a
really if you go that's a fun Rabbit
Hole go down that rabbit hole Shuff
tried really hard to hide um a project
from the internet and the internet kept
finding it over and over and over again
including like complex drone anal it's
really crazy so so um he uses jpeg these
days uh what are you using
raw you're using you're using PNG uh or
jpeg uh world's best game capture the
flag yeah Capture the Flag yeah you guys
know what I'm talking about um anyway
people were able to figure out their
location pretty easily just by looking
at pictures so um you know I think I
think some of the concern about GPS
information being saved in a picture is
is is is a little bit overblown yes it
makes it super easy but somebody who's
really determined to find you is going
to find you no matter what if you put a
picture up there publicly period they
could just you know copy the thing and
look look for it was uh El Chapo was was
capture based on image metadata nice did
not know that um so so there so there so
when that's the last thing I had to say
about it just kind of a fun thing to end
on um and um you know keep in mind that
you know stuff should be printed um I
don't know if you still care about this
but I do work with Educators and some of
them are still stuck printing things out
and giving them to their students um if
you are one of these people uh raster
images it's crazy to say this but raster
images tend to print better than svgs in
most cases if you want like a picture
type thing and I I don't I can't believe
I'm saying that most of the time you
would be printing out uh like a
screenshot or something like that you
can't do an you have a screenshot right
because it has to be raster image um and
and by the way if you think that you got
your jpeg or your PNG or screenshot to
go into an SVG it's really not it's an
SVG that's encapsulated a rasterized
image inside of it so you're still
dealing with all those little bits and
resolution and stuff like that uh yeah
and Zed Zed's mentioning the same things
right now um when you put a rasterized
image inside of an SVG um you still have
all the same considerations with regard
to rasterization and you know the change
in resolution all that stuff it still
applies it's just now hidden even more
for me because it's embedded inside of
an SVG file which is a bunch of
instructions right and um so that is way
more than you ever wanted to hear about
images that is also the only thing
you're ever going to hear me say about
images in the entire beginner boost
because you know you seriously you could
spend a days just just studying all of
this stuff um if you do like to geek out
on uh you know video and and design
issues you know stay stay tuned for some
of my IRL streams um I do a lot of uh
conversations about video compression
and and and you you know bandwidth
encoding and SRT and these are more
video things um and it's it's probably
worth mentioning that there is no and
this is the only time I'm going to
mention it there is no method of
including a video inside of a markdown
file I'm going to say it again because
somebody's going to take me to task on
this there is no current method of
embedding a in markdown in pure markdown
not with without HTML right there is no
current method of embedding a video
inside of a markdown file period so that
means linking to YouTube videos as I
have done on
skill. uh the closest you could get to
that and I've seen people do this is
they will take a screenshot image of a
of one of their videos and they will
link the image right and they will turn
the image into a link let's show you how
to do that right now so if I wanted this
to go so let's say I wanted this link of
Elliot to go someplace right let's say I
wanted it to go to skill stack I don't
know why but if I wanted this link to go
to skill stack then all I have to do and
this gets a little messy is I have to
take that image and treat it as if it
were text and then I can do the same
thing as before I can link it to I can
look at the skill stack or wherever uh
if frames iframes are not marked down
they are HTML so that why that's what I
stand by what I said so um so there you
go so you got the first Elliot link and
then we have the second one but this
second one is now hot linked see how see
how when I hold my mouse over the top of
it it has a thumb and I can click on it
and that will take me changes may not be
saved yeah we're not going to leave it
so see down here in the bottom left is
say
skill. so the point is that this one is
this one is uh is this one hot linked oh
interesting because we did that other
thing it actually is going to show us
the private image that is cool that's a
that's a GI up thing that automatically
made turned our picture into a link as
well that's that's we did not
specifically do that that it added that
um so so if you go here and you click on
here this will go to oh my God eyes
burning actually I can fix this I have I
there we go so so there um there we go
and that is that's it um so now you know
everything there is to know about images
on the
web and images in markdown and how to
link to use images to link to other
things um pandog supports M and MP4 when
converted to
HTML um yeah i' have to look at
that yeah but the real question is do
you really want to store your images
inside of your documentation repost some
of you might um in general when using
video in my opinion it's better to link
to video on YouTube even though it gives
YouTube
control um I think yeah you can you can
definitely link like click on files and
have those files be downloaded um from
your localized location whether it be a
PDF or a movie file or a sound file um
any of the multimedia sorts of things
need to be linked to um just a reminder
make sure watch the video about the
different ways to use the web uh
markdown very solidly is in the
documentation uh method of using the web
um as soon as you start talking about
video and sound and stuff like that
you're kind of moving over into sort of
the broadcast
publishing uh media sort of web usage
and um you know they do kind of go
together but if you kind of think of
those two things as two separate things
I think you'll survive more in the world
of
documentation um I of course in your
zcast and I would never GitHub if I I
have something like two three 4,000 zcas
and entries if those were all if those
all had a just even a single raster
image in them my zle casting would be so
big GitHub would probably not allow it
anymore um so I think you know
separation of media is a thing I mean
God just think about I think I'm over
what 3,000 videos on YouTube now imagine
if every one of those videos was an mp4
and I had it I was hosting on my own
server
no it would not be a thing so take
advantage of the systems we have um this
is supposed to be a video about you know
how to create images and image links uh
as well as a breakdown of the image
summarizes uh Su you got some bonus
content in there as well I guess um
thank you and we do have one more video
about markdown and that's related to
putting maths equations and stuff like
that inside of your markdown all right